The End Morning, Miss Claire.
Ready to start the day?
Oh, whoops, I'm sorry about that.
I didn't hurt you, did I?
No, but do try to be a bit more careful.
Honestly, Lene, you should know -
It's been a while since we lost Lene,
but Miss Claire's still having
a really hard time moving on.
I wish there was something I could do.
I know!
How about I whip up something
sugary and delicious for you?
Where did this idea come from?
Maybe fondant au chocolat?
Or a decadent creme brulee?
Heck, why pick one when we
can have a little of both?
A creme brulee?
Or something else!
Whatever it takes to cheer
you up and make you smile!
I am perfectly cheery, thank you.
Oh, well, okay.
Then how about a big hug? A hug?
Absolutely not.
Mmm, alright thinking.
You're beautiful and I love you!
Yes, and for the thousandth
time, I hate you.
Honestly, you're as incorrigible
as ever, aren't you?
Now stop chit-chatting
and get back to work.
Yes, ma 'am!
Oh, and before I forget, a
letter came for you earlier.
A letter from whom?
It's from a Miss Manaria Seuss.
Sister wrote to me?
My dearest Claire, I hope this
letter finds you in good health.
I apologize for the short notice,
and any surprise this may bring.
Know that my heart, unwavering.
Remains by your side.
With all my love.
I know what that means.
She's coming?
Do you want me to
hold
on?
Oh
I love you?
Only the battle for succession has been a
fearsome one and I was
driven off as a casualty.
It's not a pretty story but I
am no longer true royalty so
please I ask that you treat me
as an equal and nothing more.
It's been so
long far too long.
If you ask me I'm happy to see
you looking well well enough.
Goodness you're You're even more
beautiful than I remember. Oh, stop.
You're such a flatterer.
And who is this?
Oh, just one of the members of my staff.
Well, introduce yourself.
Greetings, I am Ray Taylor.
It's a pleasure to meet you.
I tend to miss Claire's needs,
both domestic and romantic.
Pardon?
Enough, commoner.
Stop playing games and tell
her what your job really is.
Miss Claire!
I can't just tell people
I'm your love slave.
Think of the scandal!
That is not what you are!
Use the correct term
or get out of my sight!
But if I'm not your love
slave, then what am I to you?
Servant or maid?
Take your pick!
Forgive me.
It's Ray, right?
You're really funny.
Interesting.
You're more than an ordinary
servant, aren't you?
How dare they discard
someone of your caliber?
And favor such a dullard for the throne!
King Seuss must not
appreciate true excellence.
It's not like that!
I mean, my mother isn't his legal wife.
Well, no, but...
If anything, I find solace in
being away from all the turmoil.
Family discord is never fun.
Enough on that.
I want to know more about you, Ray?
A commoner admitted to the Royal Academy?
You must be very talented.
Not at all.
She doesn't even come close to your level.
Did you think you were special?
That being a dual caster somehow
made you superior to everyone else?
Well, my dear sister here
boasts four attributes.
She's the world's only quadcaster.
Look at that adorable smug face.
She sounds like she's
bragging about her daughter.
Are you even listening to me?
I love you so much.
Obviously you are not.
Talent for magic is
something you're born with.
It's not as though I did
anything to earn this power.
Why boast about it?
How can you say that your power is
a sign that god has blessed you?
Always exaggerating. I am not.
I felt that blessing for myself.
Meeting you was a gift.
When I wouldn't trade for
anything in the world.
When I lost my mother,
I couldn't even cry.
I was paralyzed with
guilt and self-loathing.
This part of her past isn't
something the game goes into.
It's just a backdrop
to the initial setting.
Duke Francois had business to attend to.
So after his wife's death,
he left young Miss Claire at the home
of a distant relative, Count Larnak.
Which is where she met Princess Manaria.
Pleasure to meet you, my lady.
Why does such a pretty girl look so sad?
My mother...
I said something awful to her.
And I don't think I can
ever forgive myself for it.
Listen, nobody blames you, Claire.
I promise.
Those words became my salvation.
A lifeline in my mind.
How time flies.
Can you believe it's been
ten years since then?
It has.
But I still remember every
moment like it was yesterday.
I swear to you here and now that
I will always be your protector.
In that moment, it was
like you were glowing.
Una, you'll never believe this!
I met the most wonderful,
handsome, charming prince!
Oh yes, I forgot about that.
You thought I was a boy
back when we first met.
Yes, well,
you were as charming as any prince,
so you can hardly blame me for
thinking that's what you were.
I was shocked when I found
out the truth. Oh, were you?
Did you hear about that girl?
Apparently, her name's Manaria.
Yeah, and she's a princess
of the Zeus kingdom.
Wow! Are you right?
Oh my, are you alright?
This is so fun.
Yeah, I mean, I'm fine.
Thank you for your help.
Good.
I'm glad to hear it.
That was a close one.
Be safe, my dear.
Oh, no.
I've kept you waiting.
I'm sorry. Oh, don't be.
I wasn't waiting that long.
As the Amour Ceremony approaches,
today's class will delve into
Poesy, Amour, and other poems.
Let the Verses of Love guide us through
this enchanting literary journey.
Ray, have you got a moment?
I hope I'm not catching you off guard,
but I wanted to chat, and
magic makes it so easy.
Oh, but don't worry.
I can't go poking around
in your private thoughts.
I'm aware.
You're using telepathic speech,
which is wind magic, right?
Ah, I should have known
you'd be on top of it.
You know how to connect?
You already did the hardest part for
me by establishing the magic channel.
It was actually a breeze to tap into.
So, uh, what's going on? Oh, nothing.
I just wanted to know more about you.
Here we go.
Princess Manaria appears in the
game as an ally to the player.
Miss Claire always wants to spend
time with her when she's around,
which distracts Ms.
Claire and gives the player
more time with the princes.
Manaria comes in around
the middle of the game,
and she can be super
helpful for your strategy.
Because she's so useful,
she's a favor for most fans.
But she's a total
freaking buzzkill for me!
I couldn't care less about the princes,
and much prefer to rendezvous with Ms.
Claire.
So in my mind, Princess Manaria
transforms from an ally to a rival.
It's not that I'm not a fan of hers,
but the fact that she steals Ms.
Claire away sucks!
And now that makes her my enemy.
Ray?
Hello?
I'm sorry, can you still hear me?
Yes, irritatingly well.
I mean, of course I can!
Almost too clearly.
Anyway, there's not much to tell.
I'm just your average commoner.
I'm pretty sure there's nothing about
me that would remotely interest you.
Now if you'll excuse me.
Well, that's a reaction I've
never experienced before.
Now I'm even more intrigued.
I'm so impressed.
Your reading of that poem today
was amazing, Princess Manaria.
Question though,
why the shift from the
usual I dedicate this
poem to you to I deliver this poem to you?
I mean, it's cool either way.
I was just wondering.
Ah, yes.
An old form of prosody I
borrowed from an ancient poem.
You're well, Red Ray.
Would you care to join
the discussion? Oh, um,
I'm not exactly a big poetry gal,
so I'm afraid I'm going to
have to pass on that offer.
Sorry, I hope that's okay.
Seriously?
How can you say no to an
invite from Princess Manaria?
Having talent doesn't mean
you can afford to get cocky.
Wow.
Is Rey truly that brilliant?
That she is.
She can take on anyone in a magic battle.
Oh, hey, Prince Rod. Really?
Well, that sounds intriguing.
I'd like to have a bout with her.
Yeah, well, get ready.
Because you can't face her like
you would a normal opponent.
I played chess against her one
time, and she left my head spinning.
She eluded even you, Prince Rod?
Oh, yeah.
How fascinating.
But hey, if you're looking for a bout,
I'd be happy to oblige, shall we?
You know,
I was hoping I'd get
the chance to see your
minions in action while
I was here in Bower.
Is that a yes?
I hope you know what you're getting into.
Sounds like a good time to me.
You ready for this?
Hope you don't mind if I go all out.
Please be my guest.
You know, you've got a lot of people
talking about your skills as a quadcaster.
Let's see what all the fuck's about!
Wow, would you look at that!
That was excellently done!
She's fast, and her precision
is exceptional, too.
You didn't even flinch?
How about this thing? Attack!
And burst!
Oh, no, sister!
You have some firepower, Prince Rod.
The rumors sell you short. I'm impressed.
That was amazing!
Earth magic this time, is it?
Let's see, what should I do now?
It seems rather uncouth to fight
fire with fire, so maybe...
Something a little more like this?
Ice minions?
Oh, pretty bold of you to
use my own move against me.
Are you prepared to surrender?
Oh, definitely not.
And I don't think you want me to either.
So, let's do this!
I'll be curious to see just
how long you can keep up!
If he draws this out, she'll
be at a major disadvantage.
That would be true for anyone else.
Watch closely and you'll see.
Princess Manaria has an
ace or two up her sleeve.
All right, got it. Let's go!
Do you think she can still win?
Well, they've both got
plenty of fight left in them.
Only time will tell.
But she can't keep this up for long!
Rod is using his immense amount
of magical power to wear her down!
He's going to overwhelm
her just like he did Misha!
Where'd they go?
Fine. I surrender.
That was amazing!
That was a brilliant showing.
Professor Torrid. Class.
The last spell that was used?
Who can name it?
It's called Spellbreaker.
That is correct.
It analyzes a spell's composition, forces
itself into it, and undoes it completely.
It's magic that erases magic.
She can evaluate and tear apart
a spell in the middle of combat?
I had no idea that was possible.
For most people, it wouldn't be.
When it comes to water, earth,
and fire, her aptitude is high.
But in wind, she's even
stronger, ranking exceptional.
All true.
There's more to it than that, though.
Something that makes her
magic truly frightening.
Forgive my crude methods.
You're a very difficult girl
to figure out, you know that?
I get that a lot, actually.
Sister was incredible!
Yes, Spellbreaker was fantastic, but do
you know what I found more impressive?
What's that?
The way she faced Prince Rod so
boldly with no hesitation. Yeah.
It was like watching a battle between
the mythical gods of beauty and war.
Sure, if you say so.
Sure?
That's quite the tepid response.
Are you in a foul mood
for some reason? Who, me?
No, just Peachy.
Hold on a moment.
Could it be you're jealous?
Yes! That was fast!
There isn't much sense in denying it,
considering how clear I've
made my feelings for you.
Just because you've made them clear
doesn't mean that I accept them.
What can I do to make you
realize that I'm serious?
Nothing, so let's leave it at that.
Though, I suppose...
If you would show your devotion, place
an offering upon the scales for me.
Above all, the flowers of flora
will prove your love's veracity.
That's from Poesia More. Indeed.
Poesia More is a poetic retelling
of an old Bauer Kingdom legend.
The story goes that there were two suitors
who fell in love with the same priestess.
Both were powerful men, so the conflict
between them echoed through the nation,
plunging it into chaos.
Troubled to be the source of such strife,
the priestess prayed and God presented her
with a set of scales
along with these words.
Let those who would wed you place
their offerings upon these scales.
They will tip in favor of the
man who is to be your husband.
In accordance with the scale's judgment,
the priestess married the man
who offered flowers of flora.
As for the man who lost in love, he
went on to become an excellent king.
From that ancient legend
came the Amur ceremony,
which is still performed to this day.
Hold on.
You mean, the scales of love mentioned
in Poesia Amur really do exist?
They're most likely
some kind of magic tool.
Items with magic stones in
them have been around for ages.
People have used them since long
before we knew how they worked.
Suitors' offerings are still placed upon
the scales of love
during the Amor ceremony.
Even now, people use it to choose
who they're going to marry.
Sort of like a cross between an
arranged marriage and a duel.
Or a high-stakes
reenactment of Poesia Amor.
Famed artifact or not,
very few people are truly willing to entrust
their futures to such a farcical game.
And there are those
who use the ceremony as
an excuse to confess
their love every time.
People are always waiting to see
who will confess and to whom what?
A fascinating tradition and so romantic!
I see now why everyone
is so giddy about it!
So?
Who among us will be putting their
love to the test on the scales?
You can sit this one out, Claire?
You've already got Ray Prince, you.
Another mystery solved, so that's
how it is between the two of you?
Then the last thing I need
is someone else spouting this
nonsense and that's what it
is—the girl is only teasing me,
nothing more.
You still really believe I'm not being
sincere about my feelings for you?
So it's unrequited love on Ray's part?
Hmm—love given but not
returned or acknowledged.
Well, well.
And anyway,
if I were to court a
partner of the same gender,
I would obviously choose sister over you.
Must be hard to hear, huh?
As much as you may adore her,
Claire says that she prefers me.
Goodness—this is
a rather sudden display of affection.
Tell me, if I said that I loved
you, would you believe me, Claire?
Of course I would.
In all these years, I've never
doubted the sincerity of your love.
Don't let your head explode, Ray.
Cute numbers or something?
Sister, stop—I'm blushing.
2, 3, 5, 7,
11, 13, 17, 19, 23, 29, 31, 37, 31?
Those two get along well?
They must be quite close?
must be quite close More tea, anyone?
All this chatting must be thirsty work.
Thank you, but that isn't the teapot.
It's the milk pitcher.
Right, terribly sorry about that.
You look rather pale.
Have you fallen ill?
Oh no, I'm perfectly fine I
appreciate the concern, though.
What about when's name?
He's the one you're
supposed to be in love with,
not that quad-testing royal interloper.
Should I have said when?
Wow ...
Oh
I don't know.
I'm going to die.
I'm not going to die.